The first time I uttered a prayer was in a glass-stained cathedral.
أول مرة أنطق فيها بصلاة كانت داخل زجاج الكاتدرائية الملون.
I was kneeling long after the congregation was on its feet,
كنت راكعة لفترة طويلة بينما المصلون واقفون،
dip both hands into holy water,
غمست كلتا يدي في الماء المقدس،
trace the trinity across my chest,
رسمت الثالوث على صدري،
my tiny body drooping like a question mark
جسدي الصغير منحني كعلامة إستفهام
all over the wooden pew.
على كل المقاعد الخشبية.
I asked Jesus to fix me,
سألت المسيح أن يصلحني،
and when he did not answer
و حين لم يُجب
I befriended silence in the hopes that my sin would burn
لزمت الصمت على أمل أن تمحى خطيئتي
and salve my mouth
و تُحل عقدة لساني
would dissolve like sugar on tongue,
و أن يذوب كما السكر على اللسان،
but shame lingered as an aftertaste.
لكن طعم العار كان يظهر لي ببطء.
And in an attempt to reintroduce me to sanctity,
و كمحاولة لإعادة تعريف نفسي للقداسة،
my mother told me of the miracle I was,
أخبرتني أمي عن كوني الطفل المعجزة،
said I could grow up to be anything I want.
قائلة أن بإمكاني أن أصبح ما أريد حين أكبر
I decided to
قررت
be a boy.
أن أكون ولدا.
It was cute.
كان ذلك ظريفا.
I had snapback, toothless grin,
كان لدي قبعة و إبتسامة خاوية،
used skinned knees as street cred,
أستخدم ركبتي العارية لإغراء الشارع،
played hide and seek with what was left of my goal.
في حالة ضياع و تلاقي مع ما تبقى من حلمي،
I was it.
كنت كذلك.
The winner to a game the other kids couldn't play,
كنت الفائزة في لعبة لا يستطيع أحد آخر أن يلعبها،
I was the mystery of an anatomy,
كنت شيئا غامضا في عالم التشريح،
a question asked but not answered,
سؤال لم يٌجب عليه،
tightroping between awkward boy and apologetic girl,
متأرجحة بين كوني ولدا أخرقا أو بنتا خجولة،
and when I turned 12, the boy phase wasn't deemed cute anymore.
عندما بلغت 12، لم يعد شكل الولد جذابا كما كان.
It was met with nostalgic aunts who missed seeing my knees in the shadow of skirts,
قوبل ذلك بحنين عمات افتقدن مشاهدة ركبتي مرتدية تنورة،
who reminded me that my kind of attitude would never bring a husband home,
ذكروني بأن هذا النوع من التصرفات لن يجلب لي زوجاً،
that I exist for heterosexual marriage and child-bearing.
و أن سبب وجودي هو الزواج و إنجاب الأطفال
And I swallowed their insults along with their slurs.
قبلت شتائمهن و إفترائاتهن.
Naturally, I did not come out of the closet.
بالطبع، لم أخرج من قوقعتي الصغيرة.
The kids at my school opened it without my permission.
الأطفال في مدرستي فتحوها عنوة.
Called me by a name I did not recognize,
نادوا علي باسم لم أعرفه،
said "lesbian,"
قالوا "سحاقية"،
but I was more boy than girl, more Ken than Barbie.
كنت صبيا أكثر من كوني أنثى، كنت كين أكثر من كوني باربي.
It had nothing to do with hating my body,
ليس لذلك علاقة بكرهي لجسدي،
I just love it enough to let it go,
أنا فقط أحببته لدرجة جعله ينمو،
I treat it like a house,
عاملته كمنزل لي،
and when your house is falling apart,
و عندما يهوي منزلك،
you do not evacuate,
لا تغادره،
you make it comfortable enough to house all your insides,
تجعله مريحا كفاية كي تحمي كل ما لديك بداخله،
you make it pretty enough to invite guests over,
تجعله جميلا كي تدعو الضيوف إليه،
you make the floorboards strong enough to stand on.
تجعل الأرضية قوية كفاية كي تقف عليها.
My mother fears I have named myself after fading things.
أمي تخاف أني ألاحق أشياء لاوجود لها.
As she counts the echoes left behind by Mya Hall,
و بينما هي تتذكر الأصداء التي خلفتها مايا هول و
Leelah Alcorn, Blake Brockington.
ليلا آركون و بلاك بروكينغتون.
She fears that I'll die without a whisper,
تخاف أن أموت من دون حتى إنذار،
that I'll turn into "what a shame" conversations at the bus stop.
أن أتحول إلى مثار للعار في محطة الباص.
She claims I have turned myself into a mausoleum,
إدعت أمي أنني حولت نفسي إلى ضريح،
that I am a walking casket,
و بأنني مثل تابوب يمشي،
news headlines have turned my identity into a spectacle,
عناوين الأخبار حولت هويتي إلى مشهد مسرحي،
Bruce Jenner on everyone's lips while the brutality of living in this body
إنجازات بروس جينير على كل لسان مع وحشة العيش داخل هذا الجسد
becomes an asterisk at the bottom of equality pages.
أصبحت كعلامة في آخر صفحات المساواة،
No one ever thinks of us as human
لا أحد يفكر فينا كبشر مطلقا
because we are more ghost than flesh,
لأننا أشباح أكثر منا لحما و دما،
because people fear that my gender expression is a trick,
لأن الناس تخاف أن تعابير جسدي بمثابة خدعة،
that it exists to be perverse,
بأنه وُجد ليكون منحرفاً،
that it ensnares them without their consent,
بأنّه يوقعهم في فخ دون رضاهم،
that my body is a feast for their eyes and hands
بأن جسدي مهرجان لأعينهم و أيديهم
and once they have fed off my queer,
و بمجرد أن يكتفوا من جسدي،
they'll regurgitate all the parts they did not like.
سيرفضوا كل الأجزاء التي لا يحبونها.
They'll put me back into the closet, hang me with all the other skeletons.
سيعيدونني إلى الخزانة، و يعلقونني مع بقية الهياكل.
I will be the best attraction.
سأكون الأكثر جاذبية.
Can you see how easy it is to talk people into coffins,
هل لكم أن تتصوروا كم من السهل محاكاة موت الناس،
to misspell their names on gravestones.
أن تخطئوا قراءة شواهد قبورهم.
And people still wonder why there are boys rotting,
و ما زال الناس يتسائلون لماذا يفسد الأولاد،
they go away in high school hallways
يتهربون من المدرسة الثانوية
they are afraid of becoming another hashtag in a second
هم خائفون أن يصبحوا فجأة وسماً أخر
afraid of classroom discussions becoming like judgment day
يخافون أن تصبح النقاشات داخل فصول المدرسة كيوم الحساب
and now oncoming traffic is embracing more transgender children than parents.
و الآن الجنس القادم يحتضن أطفالاً مخنثين أكثر من الأباء.
I wonder how long it will be
أتسائل كم سيستمر هذا
before the trans suicide notes start to feel redundant,
قبل أن تصبح مذكرات ما بعد الإنتحار شيئا عاديا،
before we realize that our bodies become lessons about sin
قبل ان ندرك أن أجسادنا أصبحت درسا عن الإثم
way before we learn how to love them.
قبل أن نتعلم كيف نحبهم.
Like God didn't save all this breath and mercy,
و كأن الإله لم يرحم و يحفظ كل هذه الأرواح،
like my blood is not the wine that washed over Jesus' feet.
و كأن دمي ليس النبيذ الذي غسل من تحت قدمي المسيح.
My prayers are now getting stuck in my throat.
صلواتي الآن باتت تخنقني.
Maybe I am finally fixed,
ربما أخيرا أصلحني،
maybe I just don't care,
ربما لم أعد أهتم،
maybe God finally listened to my prayers.
ربما استمع الإله أخيرا لصلواتي.
Thank you.
شكرا